ladies done the president of the united
states the
hard
haha
her heart
but
thank you so much for my plans are the
same
have the same are before I get started
can we get the new
presidential set up at her up
it's worked before
that's more like it it is great to be
back what a year
I usually start these dinners with a few
self-deprecating jokes after my stellar
2013 what could I possibly talk about
I'm it last year was rough
sheesh at one point
things got so bad the 47 percent
called Mitt Romney to apologize
of course
we're all that healthcare dug up
on that could have gone better
into that made my slogan was yes we can
in 2013 my slogan was control
alt delete
on the plus side
they did turn the launch of healthcare
dug up
in the one of the year's biggest movies
I
but rather than dwell on the past
I would like to pivot to this matter but
welcome our headliner
the cement Joel McHale in
on community job plays a preening
themselves
obsessed narcissist so this dinner must
be real change your plans for the
I wanna thank
the White House Correspondents
Association for hosting us here tonight
I am happy to be here even though I am a
little jet-lagged from my trip to
Malaysia
the links we have to go to to get
CNN coverage these days I
in
I think they're still searching for
their table
MSNBC is here girl overwhelmed
they've never seen an audience this big
before I
her but look at everybody is trying to
keep up with this
incredibly fast changing media landscape
for example a law degree
on cable news for promoting Obamacare
to young people going on between two
firms but that's what young people like
to watch
and to be fair I'm not the first person
on television
between to potted plants I
sometimes I do feel disrespected by
reporters
but that's okay Seattle Seahawk
cornerback Richard Sherman is here
tonight and he gave me
communism great tips on how to handle it
Jake Tapper
don't you ever talk about me like that
on the bus problem today
by then Richard reckon
lamar prelim exe
while we're talking sports just last
month
a wonderful story American one the
Boston Marathon for the first time in 30
years
which was inspired and only fair since a
canyon has been present for the last six
I
even things up
her
we have some other athletes here tonight
including
Olympic snowboarding gold medalist Jamie
Anderson is here
proud of her incredibly talented young
lady Michelle know what cylinders we
cannot believe what these folks built
death-defying feats haven't seen so many
Paulo
180 that person's Rand Paul
this in mind that nevada rancher from is
better
occur
a general rule
things dome the n well
if the seven starts let me tell you
something I know about the negro
I
you don't need to hear the rest up
doesn't support
don't start your sons that work
her
I
spending around Paul
Colorado legalized marijuana this year
well an interesting social experiment a
I do hope it does lead to a whole lot
paranoid people who think that the
federal government's
out to get them listening to their phone
calls
that would be a problem
and speaking up conservative euros
the Koch brothers market table here
tonight
but as usual the use the shadowy
right-wing organization
as a spot hello partners I
under under skating but space box you
miss me when I'm gone
will be harder to convince the American
People that
hillary was born in Kenya I
Co
a lot of us really are concerned about
the way big-money is influencing our
politics
I remember when a super PAC was just me
by Marlboro 100's instead irregulars
course now
that its 2014 Washington is obsessed
on the midterms folks are saying that
with my sagging poll numbers
my fellow democrats don't really want me
campaigning with and I don't think
that's true
although I did notice the other day that
sashimi the speaker a career day and she
invited bill clinton's I
I was a are all heard
what we're doing whatever it takes to
win
a ruthless game republicans
the true story republicans actually
brought in a group of consultants to
teach their candidates
how to speak to women this trial
are and I don't know if it'll work with
women but I understand that
america's teenage boys are signing up to
one for the senate and rolls
anyway why you guess what was on a
horse-race I'm gonna do what I do I'm
gonna be focused
on everyday Americans just yesterday I
read a heart-breaking letter
you know I get letters from folks around
the country every day I get 10 that I
read
this this one got to maim a Virginia man
has been stuck in the same part time job
for years
no respect from his boss no chance to
get ahead
I really wish or can we stop writing
in
we gonna pick up owner
and I'm feeling
sorry believe it or not for the speaker
has as well
these days the house republicans
actually give john bainer a harder time
than they give me
which means orange really is the new
black
I in
but I have not given up they are working
with congress in fact two weeks ago
senator Ted Cruz and I we got a bill
done together
and I have to say the signing ceremony
was something special picture but either
I
I'm not gonna
what Washington seems more dysfunctional
than ever
gridlock has gotten so bad in this town
your you have to wonder what we do to
piss off chris Christie so bad I
one issue for example where minimal
agree on is unemployment insurance
republicans continue to refuse to extend
a you know what I am beginning to think
they've got a point if you want to get
paid
while not working usual a 2-1 for
congress just like everybody else
of course there is one thing the key
problems mister
they have tried more than 50 times to
repeal Obamacare
despite that eight million people sign
up for health care in the first open
enrollment
much does believe one as how well the
Obamacare
have to work before you don't wanna
repealing whatever but his cholesterol
drops want
wanna your yearly checkup came
what tickets to a Clippers game
but not the old answer link occurs the
new Oprah Clippers
I for them love for the day
much more co-op all I
one is it gonna take
any word
this year are promised to use more
executive actions
to get things done without congress by
critics call this the Emperor
period presidents true there's I don't
show up every day my office and do my
job
a picture of this I think
you would but better person
a more assertive approach considering
the the new conservative darling
is none other than Blatter perm last
year
pat buchanan said whose headed straight
for the Nobel Peace Prize
the service at nine oh that sounds crazy
I'll
but to be fair they give those to just
about anybody these days
I so it could happen
but not just path Rudy Giuliani said
porn is what you call a leader Mike
Huckabee and shot him to keep talking
about his bare chest
we just got word I
look it up but talk about it a lot
it is strange to think that I just
two-and-a-half years left in this office
I'm everywhere I look for reminders that
I only hope this job temporary work
or but its long time between now and
2016 and anything can happen
you may have heard the other day hillary
had to dodge applying shoe
at a press conference I
I love her picture could regardless of
what happened that on my last campaign
and I'm beginning to think about my
legacy something all
a mirror on the menu recently announced
she's aiming high school after me in
chicago which
is extremely homework I was even more
clarity here
Rick Perry was here tonight is doing the
same thing in taxes
take a look I
correct
there's a lot to me
that I intend to enjoy
all the free time but I will hear George
W Bush
took up painting after he left office
which inspired me to get my own artistic
side I i'm sure we got a shot at this
maybe not the job doesn't work without
the slight
I
oh well
assume it was fun
doesn't have a new joke
that does ok on a more serious note
tonight reminds us that we really are
likely to live in a country where
reporters
get to give your head a State a hard
time on a daily basis
and then once a year give him or her
the chance at least to try to return the
favor
but we also know that not every
journalists
or photographer or crew member is so
fortunate because even as we celebrate
the Free Press tonight our thoughts are
with those in places
around the globe like ukraine and
Afghanistan
and Syria in Egypt a risk
everywhere in some cases even give their
lives
to report the news and what tonight also
reminds us
is better the fight for full and fair
access goes beyond the chance to ask a
question
as steam engine decades ago an
african-american who wanted
to cover his or her president might be
barred from journalism school
burden by Jim Crow and once marching
band
from press conferences but after years
about her
bike editors and publishers began
meeting with FDR's
press secretary Steve or many met with
the president himself
to declare that a black reporter would
get a credential
and even when very much help in made
history as the first african-american
to attend a presidential news conference
he was always welcome
by the other reporters we was welcomed
by the press
who told him I'm glad to see mcalpine
I'm very happy to have you here nuts are
settlement might have one of one serious
one questioner took
& Harry's battles continue but he made
history and we're so proud of
Sherman and his family for being here
tonight
and the White House Correspondents
Association for creating a scholarship
and Harry's neck here
for over 100 years even as the White
House Correspondents Association has
told
story america's progress you would the
two
gradually long equal access to women
minorities and gays Americans with
Disabilities
and yes radio and television and
Internet reporters as well
and through it all you've helped make
sure that even as
societies change are fundamental
commitment to
the interaction between those who govern
and those who ask questions
doesn't change and is Jay will attest
its legacy you carry on enthusiastically
every single there
and because this is the one hundredth
anniversary
other correspondence association I
actually
record additional brief video thanking
olive you for your hard work
we run the video Grange
what's going on I R I was told this
would work
does am I not affect rest
I'll thank you I
that
yeah see it all the time
that's where I'm just
while sold years home
world really years thank you very much
sir but I got much
god bless america
plans about are