the
thank you so much thank you
thank you very much thank you please
please have a seat good evening
with Tom
boss while good Nabhan
the thank you Laura
for that remarkable introduction on
before she came out
she told me not to be nervous
and I can only imagine
I think her father's me audience and I
can only imagine how proud he is
upper we're grateful for her work but
she's also
reminding us that our future will be
defined
by young people like ur your majesties
mister prime minister and
the people a Belgium on behalf of the
American people
we are grateful for your friendship we
stand together as
inseparable allies and I thank you for
your wonderful hospitality
I have to admit it is easy to love a
country famous for chocolate
and beer
leaders and dignitaries
a big European Union representatives of
our nato alliance
distinguished guests we meet here
at a moment's have tested for europe
in the United States and for the
International order
that we have worked for generations to
build throughout human history societies
have grappled
with fundamental questions of how to
organize themselves
the proper relationship between
the individual in the state the best
means to resolve all
inevitable conflicts between states and
it was here in your
through centuries a struggle
dewar enlightenment repression
and revolution that a particular
said abide eels began to emerge the
belief that
to conscience and free will each of us
has the right
to live as we choose the belief that
power is just
derived from the consent up the
government and the laws and institutions
should be established
to protect better understand those ideas
eventually inspired a band of
colonialists
across an ocean and they wrote them into
the founding documents
but still got america today including
the simple truth that
all men and women are created a
but those ideals
have also been tested here in Europe men
around the world
those ideals have often been threatened
by older
more traditional your power as
alternative vision argues that
ordinary men and women are two
small-minded to govern their own affairs
that order and progress can only come
when
individual surrender their rights to an
all powerful sovereign
often
this alternative vision route itself in
the notion the by virtual race
or fake ethnicity some are inherently
superior to others
and that individual identity must be
defined by
us versus them or that
national greatness must flow not by what
people stand for but
what they are against in so many ways
the history of Europe in the 20th
century represented the ongoing clash
these two sets Abidi its both within
nations and among nations
the offensive industry and technology
outpace our ability to resolve our
differences peacefully
and evening even among the most
civilized societies on the surface we
saw
descent in the barbers this morning at
Flanders field I was reminded the power
war between peoples sent a generation to
their deaths
in the trenches and gas
the First World War in just two decades
later
extreme nationalism plunged this cotton
into war
once again with populations and slave
and great cities reduced to rubble
and tens of millions slaughtered
including those lost
in the Holocaust it is in
response to this tragic history that in
the aftermath of World War two
America join with europe to reject the
darker forces in the past
and build a new architecture apiece
workers and engineers
gave life to the Marshall Plan Sentinel
stood vigilant in the nato alliance that
would become the strongest the world has
ever known
and across the Atlantic we embraced a
shared vision a viewer
a vision based on representative
democracy individual rights
and a belief that nations can meet the
interests
other citizens through trade and open
markets a social safety net
respect for those a different faiths and
backgrounds
for decades this vision stood
in sharp contrast to life on the other
side of an iron curtain
for decades
a contest was wage and ultimately that
contest
was one not by tanks or missiles
but because our ideals stirred the
hearts of Hungarians who sparked a
revolution
polls in there shipyards who stood
in solitaire checksum
waged a velvet revolution. without
firing a shot and east berliners
march past the guards and finally tore
down that wall
today
what would have seemed impossible in the
trenches
flanders the rubble in Berlin dissidence
prison cell that reality
is taken for granted
a germany unified the nations of Central
and Eastern Europe welcomed into the
family democracies
here in this country once the
battleground have your
we meet in the heart other union that
brings together
age old adversaries and peace and
cooperation
the people love your hundreds of
millions of citizens
east west north south are more secure
and more prosperous
because we stuck together for the ideals
we share
and the story of human progress was by
no means limited to your
indeed the the ideals that came to
define our alliance
also inspired movements across the
global
among those very people ironically who
were too often been denied therefore
rights by Western powers
after the second world war people from
Africa India through of
the ok colonialism to secure their
independence
in the united states citizens to freedom
rights
and/or beatings to put an end to
segregation and the secure
their civil rights
as the iron curtain fell here near the
iron fist apartheid was on clenched
and nelson mandela emerged upright
proud from prison
to lead a multi-racial democracy
Latin American nations rejected
dictatorship and build new democracies
an Asian nation show the development and
democracy
could go hand in hand
the young people in the audience today
young people like your work were born in
a place and a time
where there is less conflict more
prosperity
and more freedom than any time in human
history
but that's not because
man's darkest impulses have vanished
even here in Europe we've seen ethnic
cleansing
in the balkans that shocked the
conscience the difficulties
integration and globalization recently
amplified by the worst economic crisis
in our lifetimes
strained the European project and stir
the rise above politics that
too often targets immigrants or gays
or those who some seem somehow different
what technologies opened up vast
opportunities for trade in innovation
and cultural understanding
it's also allow terrorists to kill on a
horrifying scale
around the world sectarian warfare and
ethnic complex continue to claim
thousands of lives and once again
we are confronted with the belief among
some butt bigger nations can bully
smaller ones to get their way
that recycled maxim that
might somehow makes right
so I come here today tensest that we
must never take for granted
the progress that has been one here in
Europe and advanced around the world
because the contest ideas continues
for your generation and that's what's at
stake
in Ukraine today
Russia's leadership is challenging truce
but only a few weeks ago seem
self-evident
that in the 21st century the borders and
Europe cannot be
redrawn with force that international
law matters
the people and nations can make their
own decisions about their future
to be honest if we define arnie are
our interests Marily if we apply to a
cold-hearted calculus
we might decide to look the other way
our economy is not deeply integrated
with
ukraine's our people and our homeland
face no direct threat
from invasion a prime your our own
borders are not threatened by Russia's
annexation
but that kind of casual indifference
would ignore the lessons that are
written in the cemetery's
on this comment it would allow
the old way of doing things to regain a
foothold
in this young century and that message
would be hard not just in Europe for
but in Asian in the Americas in Africa
and the Middle East and the consequences
that would arise from complacency are
not
abstractions the impact
that they have on the lives real people
men and women just like us after
enter into our imaginations
just look at the young people in Ukraine
were determined to take back for future
from a government
rotted by corruption the portrait serve
the Fallen shot by snipers the visitors
who pay
their respects the meda there was the
university student wraps
in the ukrainian flag expressing our
hope that every country should live by
the law
a postgraduate students speaking
a for fellow protesters saying
I want these people we're here to have
dignity imagine
that you are the young woman who said
there are some things that
fear police sticks and tear gas cannot
destroy we've never met
these people but we know them their
voices
echo calls for human dignity that rang
out in European streets and squares for
generations
their voices echoed those around the
world
who at this very moment fight for their
good these ukrainians rejected a
government that was stealing
from the people instead of serving them
and are reaching for the same ideals
that allow us to be here today
none of us can know for certain what the
coming days
will bring in Ukraine but I am confident
that eventually those voices
those voices for human dignity and
opportunity and individual rights
Andrew love law those voices ultimately
will try I believe that over the long
haul
as nations they're free
Esprit people the future is hours
I believe this not because
I'm naive and I believe this not because
the strength of our arms or the size
Arcana means I believe this because
these ideals that we affirm
are true his ideals are universal
yes we believe in democracy
with elections that are free and fair
an independent judiciary is opposition
parties
civil society and uncensored
information to the individuals can make
their own choices
yes
we believe in open economies based on
free markets and innovation an
individual initiative and
entrepreneurship
and trade and investment that creates a
broader prosperity
and yes we believe in human dignity
that every person has created equal no
matter who you are or what you look like
or who you love or where you come from
that is what we believe that's what
makes us
strong
and our enduring strength is also
reflected in our respect for an
international system that protects the
rights of both nations and people
a united nations
and Universal Declaration of Human
Rights international law and the means
to enforce
those laws but we also know that those
rules
are not self-executing they depend on
people and nations a good will
continually
a birmingham and that's why russia's
violation up
international law its assault on
Ukraine's
sovereignty and territorial integrity
must be met with condemnation
not because we're trying to keep russia
down
but because the principles meant so much
to europe and the world
must be lifted up
over the last several days the United
States Europe in our partners around the
world
have been united in defense of these
ideas
and united in support of the Ukrainian
people together we've condemned
Russia's invasion of Ukraine and
rejected the legitimacy
the Crimean referendum together
we have isolated russia politically
suspending it from the g8 nations
and downgrading our bilateral ties
together we are imposing costs through
sanctions
that have left a mark on russia and
those accountable for its actions
and if
the russian leadership stays on its
current course together
we will ensure that this isolation
deepens
sanctions will expand and the toll on
russia's economy
as well as its standing in the world
will only increase
meanwhile the United States and our
allies
will continue to support the government
of Ukraine as they chart
a democratic course together we are
gonna provide a significant package of
assistance that can help stabilize the
ukrainian economy
meet the basic needs the people
make no mistake
neither the United States nor Europe has
any interest in controlling ukraine
we have sent no troops there what we
want
is for the Ukrainian people to make
their own decisions just like
other pre people around the world
understand as well this is not another
cold war that we're entering into
after all unlike the Soviet Union Russia
leads no bloc nations no global
ideology the United States
and nato do not seek any conflict with
Russia in fact for more than 60 years we
have come together in nato
not to claim other lands but to keep
nations free
what we will do
always is up all our solemn obligation
our article 5 duty
to defend the sovereignty and
territorial integrity of our allies
and then that promise we will never
waver
they donations
never stand alone
today nato planes patrol the skies over
the baltics
and we reinforced our presence and Paul
and we're prepared to do more
going forward every
NATO member state must step up and carry
it sure the Burke
by showing the political will to invest
in our collective defense
and by developing the capabilities to
serve as a source
international peace and security
a course Ukraine is not a member of nato
in part because it's close and complex
history with Russia nor will russia be
dislodged
from Crimea or deterred from further
escalation
by military force but what time
so long as we remain united
the russian people will recognize that
they cannot achieve
security prosperity and the status that
they see
through brute force
that's why throughout this crisis we
will combine our substantial pressure on
Russia
with an open door for diplomacy I
believe that
for both Ukraine and Russia a stable
peace will come through de escalation
direct dialogue between Russian
and the government of Ukraine and the
international community monitors who can
shorter
but the rights of all Ukrainians are
protected a process of constitutional
reform within ukraine
and free and fair elections the spring
so far russia has
resisted diplomatic overtures annexing
crimea massing large forces along
ukraine's more
russia's just five these actions as an
effort to
prevent problems on its own borders and
to protect
ethnic russians inside ukraine of course
there's no evidence
never has been up
systemic violence against ethnic
russians inside if ukraine
moreover many countries around the world
face similar questions about their
borders and ethnic minorities abroad
about sovereignty and self-determination
is a tensions that have led
in other places to debate and democratic
referendums
complex
and uneasy coexistence these are
difficult issues and it is precisely
because
these questions are hard that they must
be addressed through constitutional
means
and international laws senate majorities
cannot simply suppress my north's
and big countries cannot simply bully
the small
in defending its actions russian leaders
a further claim
Kosovo as a precedent an example
they save the West interfering in the
affairs a smaller country
just as they're doing now but made only
intervene
after the people a possible were
systematically brutalized and killed
four years and possible only let serbia
after a referendum was organized not
outside the boundaries of international
law but in careful cooperation with the
United Nations
and with Kosovo's neighbors love that
even came close to happening in Crimea
more Russia as pointed to america's
decision to go into Iraq
as an example of Western hypocrisy now
it is true
that the Iraq war was a subject vigorous
to make I just around the world but
in the United States as well I
participated Matt Baker
and I posed or military intervention
there
but even
in a iraq America sought to work
within the international system we did
not claim
or annex iraq's territory we did not
grab its resources for our own game
and said we ended our war
and left a rock to its people and a
fully sovereign
Iraqi state that can make decisions
about its on future
of course neither the United States nor
Europe
are perfect in adherence
to our ideas nor do we claim to be the
sole arbiter
what is right or wrong in the world we
are human after all
and we face difficult decisions
about how to exercise our power but part
of what makes
us different is that we welcome
criticism just as we welcome
the responsibilities that com with
global leadership
we look to the east and the South MC
nations poised to play a growing role
on the world stage and we consider that
a good thing it reflects the same
diversity that makes us stronger as a
nation and the foursome integration and
cooperation that
Europe has advanced for decades and in
the world
challenges that are increasingly global
all of us have an interest in nations
stepping forward to play their part to
bear their share the burden
and two uphold international norms
so our approach stands in stark contrast
to the arguments coming out in russia
these days it is absurd
to suggest as a steady drumbeat of
Russian voices do that America
somehow conspiring with fascists inside
of Ukraine for failing to respect
the russian people my grandfather served
in patton's armor
just as many of your fathers and
grandfathers fought against fascism
we americans remember well
the unimaginable sacrifices made by the
russian people in world war two
and we have honored those sacrifices
since the end of the cold war
we have worked with Russia under
successive administrations
to build ties a culture and commerce
and international community but as a
favor to russian
but because a was in our national
interests and together we've secured
nuclear materials from terrorists we
welcome rush into the G-eight
and the World Trade Organization from
the reduction of nuclear arms to the
elimination of Syria's chemical weapons
we believe the world has benefited when
Russia
chooses to cooperate on the basis a
mutual interests and mutual respect
so America and the world
and Europe has an interest in a strong
and responsible Russian not a week 1 we
want the russian people to live in
security
prosperity and dignity like everyone
else proud of their own history
but that does not mean that russia can
run roughshod over its neighbors
just because russia has a deep history
with ukraine does not mean it should be
able to dictate
Ukraine's future no amount of propaganda
can make right
something that the world nose is wrong
and then every society must chart
its own course america's pair
or Europe spare is not the only
ways to reach freedom and justice but on
the fundamental principle that is at
stake here
the ability of nations and peoples to
make their own choices
there can be no going back
it's not america the
filled the Maidan with protesters it was
ukrainians
no foreign forces compelled
the citizens a Tunis and Tripoli to rise
up
they did so on their own
from the Burmese parliamentarian
pursuing reform to the young leaders
fighting corruption
and intolerance in Africa we see
something irreducible
that all OVA share as human beings a
truth that will persevere in the face of
violence
and repression and what ultimately
overcome
for the young people here today I know
it may seem
easy to see these offenses removed from
our lights
remote from our daily routines
distant from concerns closer to home I
recognize the both
in the United States and in much of
Europe there's more than enough to worry
about
in the affairs of our own countries
there will always be voices who say that
what happens in the wider world is not
are concerned nor our responsibility but
we must never forget that we are here's
to a struggle for freedom our democracy
our individual opportunity
only exist because those who came before
us have the wisdom
and the courage to recognize the ideals
will only indoor
if we see ourselves interest in the
success other people's
and other nations
now is not the time for bluster the
situation in Ukraine
my crises in many parts of the world
does not have easy answers
nor a military solution but at this
moment
we must meet the challenge to our ideas
to our very international order
with strength and conviction and
it is you young people
a your young people like your
who will help decide which way
the currents our history will flow
do not think for a moment that your own
freedom
your own prosperity that your own moral
imagination is bound
by the limits love your community
her ethnicity
or even your country you're bigger than
their
you can help
us to choose a better history that's
what europe tells us
that's what the American experience is
all about
I say this as the president of a country
that
look to europe for the values that are
written into our founding documents
and which spilled blood to ensure that
those values could
indoor on the shores I also say
this as the son of a Kenyan whose
grandfather was a cook for the British
and as a person who once lived in
Indonesia as a
emerge from colonialism the ideals that
unite us
matter equally to the young people a
Boston
or Brussels or Jakarta
or Nairobi a cracka
archaea
in the end the success of our ideals
comes down to us
including the example our own lives
our own societies we know that they're
always be intolerance but instead of
fearing the immigrant
we can welcome we can insist on policies
that benefit the many not just a few
that
and agent globalization dizzying change
opens the door
about portunity to the marginalized and
not just
a privileged few instead of targeting
are gay and lesbian brothers
and sisters we can use our laws to
protect the rights instead of defining
ourselves in opposition to others we can
affirm the aspirations that we hold in
common
that's what will make America strong
that's what
will make Europe strong that's what
makes us who we are
and just as we meet our responsibilities
and
individuals we must be prepared to meet
them as nations
because we live in a world
in which our ideals are going to be
challenged again
and again by forces that would drag us
back
in the conflict or corruption
we can't count on
others to rise to meet those tests the
policies
your government the principles are your
European Union will make
a critical difference in whether or not
the international order that so many
generations before you have strived
to create continues to move forward
or whether retreats that's the question
we almost dance what kind of your
what kind of America
what kind of world we leave behind
and I believe that if we hold firm to
our principles and are willing to back
our beliefs with courage and resolve all
then hope
will ultimately overcome fear and
freedom will continue to try and over
terror
because that is what
forever star's in the human heart
thank you very much